SABBIR HOSSAIN

Address: House No#31, North Badda, Gulshan, Dhaka-1212

Email id: sabbirtex90@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://bd.linkedin.com/in/sabbir-hossain-241a9aab

Contact no: 01674612029



CAREER ASPIRATION

A merchandising professional with academically and technically experienced and exposure to all features of merchandising geared to increase business with buying team & to achieve high-quality product awareness & planned follow up of downward orders with the knowledge on the most advanced strategies.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

• Around 3 years' experience on Merchandising in Garments Trading House.

- Can work on multitude things in a disciplined manner.
- Can sustain extreme pressure & complete shipments within the specified deadline.
- Excellent communicator and can respond quickly to solve unforeseen complications.

Merchandiser at Next Sourcing Limited (European Based-Apparel Buying Solutions).

March 2016 - Present (10 months)

Location: House No-217, Road No-2, Mirpur DOHS, Dhaka.

Web: http://nextsourcingbd.com/

Major Buyer Work for: STARTEX APS, SUIT, BTX GROUP, COOP

- Product development, Costing & Price Negotiation.
- Make proper T&A calendar for each order placed.
- Selecting correct vendor for correct product, negotiate and place order according to target price.
- Take all approval by on time submission according to TNA.
- Making an order summery and handover QC file with every details.
- Follow up on fabric, accessories and bulk production.
- Coordinating with Production, Quality, and Commercial Department.
- Ensure on time shipments with correct quality.
- Provide a maximum effort on new inquiries to convince the buyer.

Assistant Merchandiser at Texso Company Ltd (Italian Trading House). February 2014 - February 2016 (2 years)

Location: House No-1085, Road No-6(A), Sarkar Bari, Mirpur DOHS, Dhaka. **Major Buyer Work for:** TENDEM, WHALESBAY, KOTON, SPACE-2000.

- Product development from Buyer's sketch.
- Different fabrics & trims development.
- Communicating with Buyer for technical clarification, when required.
- Ensure on time submission of Lab/Yarn dip, Strike off, Quality Swatch, Fit sample, PP sample, Shipment sample and take the approval.
- Handover QC file & trims card to quality team.
- Follow up daily production activities and help to resolve the issues.
- Visit factory in every alternative week to get idea production is running according to approval & with quality as well.
- Coordination with Production, Quality, and Commercial Department.
- Follow up on time shipments

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING



Three month period Internship at "KNIT CONCERN LIMITED".
 Area of internship: Fabric Manufacturing Technology, Wet Processing Technology, Garments Manufacturing Technology & Garments Merchandising.

Project Name: "Job responsibility & challenging area of Garments Merchandiser".

- Completed two courses on "Certificate in English Language Proficiency" (CELP1, CELP2).
- Attended a training program on "Professional Advanced Excel Tips" organized by "BDJOBS".

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

SOUTHEAST UNIVERSITY, DHAKA. Bachelor of Science in Textile Engineering

2010 - 2014

Major: Garments Manufacturing Technology

Grade: 3.2 out of 4.



SHAHEED RAMIJUDDIN CANTONMENT COLLAGE, DHAKA. 2007 - 2009

Higher Secondary Certificate.

Major: Science Grade: 4.10 out of 5

BADDA ALATUNNESA HIGH SCHOOL, DHAKA.

2005 - 2007

Secondary School Certificate.

Major: Science Grade: 4.56 out of 5.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Communication Skills	IT skills	Merchandising skills
Good command in speaking, reading and writing both in Bangla and English. Efficient in negotiation.	© Competent in MS Word © Expert on MS Excel © Expert on MS Outlook © Expert in Email handling © Knowledge of MS Access	Have good idea on consumption & costing. Able to work in a systematic manner. An inspirational and adaptive team player.

CAREER AND APPLICATION INFORMATION

Looking For : Mid-Level Job

Available For : Full Time

Present Salary : Tk. 30,000

Expected Salary : Tk. 40,000

Preferred Job Category : Merchandising

Preferred Organization Types : Garment Trading House, Buying House.

PERSONAL DOSSIER

Father's Name : Hafez Abul Hossain

Mother's Name : Hasna Begum

Date of Birth : Thursday, October 11, 1990

National Id No. : 19902610413000143

Home District : Comilla

Permanent Address : S/O: Hafez Abul Hossain, Vill: Hatash (Hazi Bari),

P.O: Bangora, P.S:Muradnagar, Dist:Comilla

REFERENCE

MD. YEAKUB AHMED

Senior Merchandiser Next Sourcing Limited.

House: 217, Road: 2, Mirpur DOHS, Dhaka.

Mobile: 01717050340

E-Mail: yeakub@nextsourcingbd.com

MD. KAISAR FARUQ

Team Leader

Texso Company Limited

House: 1085, Road No: 6(A), Mirpur DOHS, Dhaka.

Mobile: 01711208295

E-Mail: faruq.texso@gmail.com